Guide to the John Jervis, Admiral Lord St. Vincent, Letters to Sir George Parker, 1800-1807 MS 308
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
John Jervis, Admiral Lord St. Vincent, Letters to Sir George Parker
1800-1807
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
St Vincent, John Jervis, Viscount
MS 308
0.1 Linear Feet (1 folder of 8 letters)
The collection consists of eight letters written to Sir George Parker, Esquire, from John Jervis, Admiral Lord St. Vincent. All letters refer to personal business and financial affairs.
Biographical Note
John Jervis, born January 9, 1735 in Meaford, received his schooling at Burton-on-Trent and Greenwich. In 1748 he entered naval service as an able seaman and was promoted to Lieutenant in 1755 on completion of his six years service. By September 1787 he had been promoted to Rear Admiral, and he became full Admiral in July 1795. Following a defeat of the Spanish fleet in early 1797, Jervis was appointed as Earl of St. Vincent. In 1801 St. Vincent accepted the position of First Lord of the Admirality which he occupied until 1806 when he returned briefly to sea duty before retiring in 1807. He was promoted to Admiral of the Fleet in 1821. Jervis was awarded the K. B. in 1782 and in 1783 entered Parliament as member for Launceston. St. Vincent died March 14, 1823.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of eight letters written to Sir George Parker, Esquire, from John Jervis, Admiral Lord St. Vincent. All letters refer to personal business and financial affairs.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Provenance
The letters were purchased with Friends of Fondren Whittington gift fund from Myers & Co., 1953-1955.
Index Terms
Document Types
corrrespondence
Subjects (Persons)
St Vincent, John Jervis, Viscount; Parker, George, Sir
- Series I: 1800-1804, 21874
  - Transfer of a deed and the building of a fence and footpath, December 25, 1800; 21877 (Folder 1)
  - Stocks; business matters, December 8, 1802; 21876 (Folder 1)
  - Refers to a letter from Parker to Mr. Ellison; offers assistance to "Edward" if he should go to Malta; also business/financial affairs, October 23, 1804; 21875 (Folder 1)
- Series II: 1805-1807, 21868
  - Business activities of Mr. Beggs, March 15, 1805; 21873 (Folder 1)
  - Reply to Mrs. Parker regarding business and personal, March 18, 1805; 21872 (Folder 1)
  - Recounts the events of a recent London visit, March 28, 1805; 21871 (Folder 1)
  - Seeking correspondence of the Athenean for a friend in Manchester, April 7, 1805; 21870 (Folder 1)
  - Requesting payment of Mr. Connington's bill; business, June 3, 1807; 21869 (Folder 1)